Guide to the Donald E. Knuth papers SC0097
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Addenda, 1996-147, Accession ARCH-1996-147
  - Errata and changes for Computers & Typesetting, June 15, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Keepsakes from the later days of TeX and METAFONT (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Duane Bibby's announcement of his new home n.d. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - TeX Christmas from Irene Hyna, December 1986 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - METAFONT Christmas card from Georgia Tobin, December 1986 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - METAFONT Valentine for Jill, February 1987 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Wedding program for Diana Barnes and Robert Nicholus, August 29, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - (one of the first uses of Computer Modern Sans Serif) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Example DVIRGB output, IBM colorjet printer by Norman Naugle, November 1987 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "A dragon for you" text and picture by Norman Naugle n.d. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Announcement of Knuth's lecture to Stanford Library Associates, December 1987 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Poster with Computer Modern, received from Oc\'e in Netherlands, April 1988 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Registration form when Knuth joined cyrTUG, the Russian TeX users group, May 1994 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Examples of TeX and METAFONT as used by Josef Gerbrich in Brno 1995 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Examples of TeX output for posted tram schedules in Brno and Prague 1995 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Early examples of TeX and METAFONT used in non-English languages: (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Irish (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Icelandic (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Russian (includes Cyrillic fonts to match Computer Modern Concrete Russian) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Old Church Slavonic (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Polish (includes Samizdat literature for Solidarity!) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Turkish (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Arabic (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Farsi (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Greek, Gothic, Hebrew, Sanskrit, etc. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - ScholarTeX by Yannis Haralambous, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - TeX et las Langues Orientales by M. Fanton and Y. Haralambous, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Amharic (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Chinese (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Japanese (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Conference publications and handouts from TeX/METAFONT user groups: (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - America - (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Delaware and Washington 1987 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Stanford 1989 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - College Station, Texas 1990 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Boston 1991 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Santa Barbara 1994 (preprints) (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Florida 1995 (preprints and handouts) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Europe - (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - First European TeX Conference, Cork, Ireland 1990 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Cahiers GUTenberg no 8 (1991) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Nordic TeX Users Group, Stockholm 1991 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Asia - (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - cyrTUG publications and fonts (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Proceedings of the 7th UNICODE conference, September 1995 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Part 1 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Part 2 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous typographic keepsakes given to Knuth by Mell Hall and Bob McCann (former employees of Stanford News and Publications) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - _____. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous typography - related keepsakes that Knuth acquired over the years: (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Demo page by leader of Lisa software at Apple Computer 1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Peter Koch, printer 1995 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Printing at the Wittington Press, 1972-1994 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Sample of Scripps College Oldstyle type (Goudy) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Typography: Basic principles and applications--Oc\'e, Netherlands (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Character language resources: International software buyer's guide 1995 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Sample graphics from 1991 Stanford Art Directors Invitational (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Samples of David Kindersley's SuperVision spacing method 1985 & 1987 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Samples of Chinese fonts by Gu Guoan, Shanghai IKARUS Limited 1989 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Early example of Dave Siegel's Tekton font, used in PhoneNET poster 1991 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Poster made at Donnelley research laboratory 1988 (poor typesetting!) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Fonts from Judith Sutcliffe of Santa Barbara (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - INRIA poster that mixes Computer Modern Sans with Univers (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence and samples from Sumner Stone's type foundry (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Font coding system used in Beijing, November 1991 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - SERIF: A typography magazine produced with TeX 1994 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Keepsake from Andrew Hoyem using types of Rudolph Koch (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Specimens of ITC Bodoni type (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - ITC font brochure 1994 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Fundacion Tipografica Neufville font brochure 1994 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Linotype font brochure 1994 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Bitstream GX fonts 1994 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - ATypI Congress 1994, San Francisco, brochure and program (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - D\"urer: So will I be perfect; keepsake by Jeff Level, Robert Kobodaishi (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous handouts from ATypI Congress 94: TypeLab, etc. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Decorated Hebrew alphabet from Jerusalem (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Erich Wronker, Picture portfolio of printing medals 1993 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Bigelow and Holmes, examples of new Lucida mathematics fonts 1992 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - A "meta-painting" (printed 1977 in Munich, but probably from 19th century) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Samples from correspondence from Sumner Stone's type foundry (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Samples from Gunnlaugur Briem (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Christmas and New Year's Cards: (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Andrea Grimes, Susie Taylor; Sheila and Julian Waters; Friedrich and Edith Neugebauer; Gunnlaugur Briem; Christine and Friedrich Peter; Gudrun and Hermann Zapf (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Brochures and Publications of TeX and/or METAFONT Vendors: (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Preliminary user guide to Micro-TeX 1986 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Donald E. Knuth und MicroTeX im Gutenbergmuseum zu Mainz, September 17, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Handouts from Jonathan Fine 1993 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Alex Warman's letter describing TeXworks publishing in Australia (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - St\"urtz typesetting of TeC documents (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - TeX-to-type at Cambridge University Press (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Look to Springer for the latest in TeXnology (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Talaris Systems Newsletters: The Laser Line 1986-1988 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Kinch Computer Company: TurboTeX buyer's guide (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Mimi Lafrenz's letter about ETP composition services in Portland (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Oc\'e's new 508dpi laserprinter with Computer Modern samples 1988 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Lance Carnes' letter about his typesetting services for DVI files 1988 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Brochure from FTL systems 1987 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Paul M. Muller's letter and proposal for Chinese typesetting 1987 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - FaSTeX flip card by Norman Paul 1986 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - ST-TeX and ST-METAFONT from TOOLS GMBH, Bonn 1986 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - The Publisher from ArborText, Inc. 1987 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Georgia Tobin's fonts (1980-1987): (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Hebrew and Decorative (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Roman (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Chel (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Slavic (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - M. D. Spivak, Mathtime fonts (PostScript Times Roman and Italic for mathematics) (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Douglas Henderson, pcMF manual (for the METAFONT system to accompany pcTeX) (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Scientific Word and Scientific WorkPlace, from TCI Software Research (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - NAR Associates: Mathematical, scientific, and historical typesetting (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Blue Sky Research brochures (1989-1995) (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Projective Solutions on converting bitmap fonts to outline fonts (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Books and publications using TeX and/or METAFONT
    - Robert Messer. Introduction to Topology 1981 (first TeX use at Vanderbilt University) (Box 7)
    - Canzii, Lucarella, & Pilenga. TeX: Primo rapporto. Milano, 1981 (Box 7)
    - Philosophie de la recherche pedagogique en Suede (first TeX book in Sweden) (Box 7)
    - Lecture Notes in Physics 189, 1983 (first book in TeX in Mexico) (Box 7)
    - Arthur Keller. Programmare in PASCAL 1984 (first book in TeX in Italy) (Box 7)
    - Middle East Studies Association Bulletin 18, 1984 (their switch to TeX) (Box 7)
    - The Political Economy of Saudi Arabia 1984 (early use of Computer Modern) (Box 7)
    - Walter Gander. Computer Mathematik 1985. (first Book in TeX in Switzerland) (Box 7)
    - D\'esarm\'enien. La division par ordinateur des nots francais 1986 (Box 7)
    - TeX in Osnabr\'uck 1986 (Box 7)
    - Tsunetoshi Hayashi. Guide to TeX implementation at Hokkaido University 1986 (Box 7)
    - Tsunetoshi Hayashi. Improvement of DVIwrite for Japanese text (Box 7)
    - NRL Memo 6044. TeXing the Formulary 1987 (shows TeX input, formulas output) (Box 7)
    - Spivak's T2D4: Tables to Die For 1987 (with illustrations by Duane Bibby) (Box 7)
    - Borde. An absolute beginner's guide to using TeX 1987 (Box 7)
    - Miguel Navarro Saad. Aztec calendar formatted with TeX macros 1987 (Box 7)
    - ABC om TeX og LsTeX n.d. (from computer center at Oslo University) (Box 7)
    - Lokale utvidelser I TeX ved USEs VAX-cluster 1988 (Oslo University) (Box 7)
    - Nobuo Saito. Sample pages of Japanese translation of the TeXbook 1988 (Box 7)
    - Peter Bruun. PiTeX: A graphical editor for pictures in LaTeX 1988 (Box 7)
    - Maarten van Emden. Slitex-sized poems for font freaks 1989 (Box 7)
    - Sherry P. Ketterer. TeXnical typesetting 1989 (by a secretary for secretaries) (Box 7)
    - Kim Kubik. Bibliography of publications related to TeX and METAFONT 1990 (Box 7)
    - User manual for Japanese TeX 1990 (Box 7)
    - Sandra Wimbish. Introduction to Pagu 1991 (interlinear texts done with TeX) (Box 7)
    - Charles Bortle. Poetry books done on his PC 1991 (Box 7)
    - Kai Borre. Mindste Kvadraters Princip 1992 (Danish book using AMS Euler) (Box 7)
    - ASCII Corporation PC software for TeX 1992 (for Japanese texts) (Box 7)
    - Vzgliahi na dom svoi, Pytnik! (one of several Russian novels published in New York) (Box 7)
    - Programmirovanie 1992 (Russian technical journal typeset in TeX) (Box 7)
    - Mnogoiazychnyi LaTeX 1993 (one of many Czech publications in TeX/METAFONT) (Box 7)
    - Magicke rostliny 1994 ("Multilingual LaTeX") (Box 7)
    - Shinsaku Fujita. Examples of chemical formulas typeset with XuMTeX 1992-1995 (Box 7)
    - W{\l}odek Byzl. Plain TeX 1995 (literate programming applied to TeX macros) (Box 7)
    - Yannis Haralambous. METAFONT improves on multiple master fonts. Preprint, 1995 (Box 7)
    - Samples by Gloria Stuart and Ward Ritchie 1994 (Box 8)
- Addenda, 1996-148 (GraphBase project records), Accession ARCH-1996-148
  Material from the making of The Stanford GraphBase, a book published by ACM Press and Addison-Wesley Publishing Company in 1993. It includes the notes I made to myself and to Stanford students during the 20-year period I was compiling material for that book. The book is based on a series of interesting computer programs and interesting data from which many experiments in computer science have been made; I expect many additional researches to be based on this system in the years to come, because experimental computer science is expanding rapidly. The book itself was named the Best New Book in Computer Science by the Association of American Publishers in 1994.
  - Notes from student meetings of the GraphBase Project (Box 1)
  - GB_BOOKS: Novels and when their characters meet (Box 1)
  - GB_ECON: Input-output data for the US economy (Box 1)
  - GB_GAMES: College football scores (Box 1)
  - GB_LISA: Pixels of Mona Lisa (Box 1)
  - GB_MILES: Highway distances between US cities (Box 1)
  - GB_ROGET: Thesaurus cross-reference (Box 1)
  - GB_WORDS: Five-letter words of English (Box 1)
  - Pencil draft of the book manuscript, except for the programs (Box 1)
  - First typeset draft of the GraphBase programs (August 1992) (Box 1)
  - Second typeset draft of the entire book (March 1993) (Box 1)
  - Copy editor's remarks (June 1993) (Box 1)
- Addenda, 1998-154 (videorecordings), Accession ARCH-1998-154
  Scope and Contents
  Computer Science 209, Mathematical Writing, lectures
  - 1987 Sep 30, 174.1; videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
  - 1987 Oct 2, 174.2; videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
  - 1987 Oct 5, 174.3; videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
  - 1987 Oct 7, 174.4; videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
  - 1987 Oct 9, 174.5; videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
  - 1987 Oct 12, 174.6; videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
  - 1987 Oct 14, 174.7; videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
  - 1987 Oct 16, 174.8; videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
  - 1987 Oct 19, 174.9; videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
  - 1987 Oct 21, 174.1; videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
  - 1987 Oct 23, 174.11; videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
  - 1987 Oct 26, 174.12; videotape (VHS) (Box 2)
  - 1987 Oct 28, 174.13; videotape (VHS) (Box 2)
    Herbert Wilf, guest lecturer
  - 1987 Oct 30, 174.14; videotape (VHS) (Box 2)
  - 1987 Nov 2, 174.15; videotape (VHS) (Box 2)
  - 1987 Nov 4, 174.16; videotape (VHS) (Box 2)
  - 1987 Nov 6, 174.17; videotape (VHS) (Box 2)
  - 1987 Nov 9, 174.18; videotape (VHS) (Box 2)
  - 1987 Nov 11, 174.19; videotape (VHS) (Box 2)
  - 1987 Nov 13, 174.2; videotape (VHS) (Box 2)
  - 1987 Nov 16, 174.21; videotape (VHS) (Box 2)
  - 1987 Nov 18, 174.22; videotape (VHS) (Box 2)
    Jeff Ullman, guest lecturer
  - 1987 Nov 20, 174.23; videotape (VHS) (Box 3)
    Leslie Lamport, guest lecturer
  - 1987 Nov 23, 174.24; videotape (VHS) (Box 3)
    Nils Nilsson, guest lecturer
  - 1987 Nov 25, 174.25; videotape (VHS) (Box 3)
    Mary-Claire van Leunen, guest lecturer
  - 1987 Nov 30, 174.26; videotape (VHS) (Box 3)
  - 1987 Dec 2, 174.27; videotape (VHS) (Box 3)
  - 1987 Dec 4, 174.28; videotape (VHS) (Box 3)
  - 1987 Dec 7, 174.29; videotape (VHS) (Box 3)
    Rosalie Stemer, guest lecturer
  - 1987 Dec 9, 174.3; videotape (VHS) (Box 3)
    Paul Halmos, guest lecturer
  - 1987 Dec 11, 174.31; videotape (VHS) (Box 3)
- Addenda, 1999-102, Accession ARCH-1999-102
  - Burroughs Corporation. Lectures on Software Design by Donald E. Knuth (photocopy), along with a computer printout: Q & D Version of Classroom Assembly Program, 1964 Fall (Box 1)
- Addenda, 2001-078, Accession ARCH-2001-078
  Correspondence, drafts, galleys, and other materials pertaining to the following publications: Selected Papers in Computer Science, Digital Typography, Analysis of Algorithms, and MMIXware.
  - Selected Papers in Computer Science
    - Correspondence, 1995-2000 (Box 1, Folder 1 (CS1))
  - Digital Typography
    - Correspondence, 1994-2000 (Box 1, Folder 2 (DT1))
    - Chapter 1: Digital Typography – drafts (Box 1, Folder 3 (DT2))
    - Chapter 2: Mathematical Typography – galleys and draft of addendum (Box 1, Folder 4 (DT 3))
    - Chapter 3: Breaking Paragraphs into Lines – galleys (Box 1, Folder 5 (DT4))
    - Chapter 4: Mixing Right-to-Left Texts with Left-To-Right Texts – galleys and proofs of illustrations (Box 1, Folder 6 (DT5))
    - Chapter 5: Recipes and Fractions – galleys and proofs of a "holly" font not used (Box 1, Folder 7 (DT6))
    - Chapter 6: The TeX Logo in Various Fonts – galleys (Box 1, Folder 8 (DT7))
    - Chapter 7: Printing Out Selected Pages – galleys and draft of addendum (Box 1, Folder 9 (DT8))
    - Chapter 8: Macros for Jill – galleys (Box 1, Folder 10 (DT9))
    - Chapter 9: Problem for a Saturday Morning – galleys (Box 1, Folder 11 (DT10))
    - Chapter 10: Exercises for TeX: The program – galleys (Box 1, Folder 12 (DT11))
    - Chapter 11: Mini-Indexes for Literate Programs – galleys (Box 1, Folder 13 (DT12))
    - Chapter 12: Virtual Fonts – galleys (Box 1, Folder 14 (DT13))
    - Chapter 13: The Letter S – galleys and draft of addendum (Box 1, Folder 15 (DT14))
    - Chapter 14: My First Experience with Indian Scripts – galleys and initial proof of Figure 1 (Box 1, Folder 16 (DT15))
    - Chapter 15: The Concept of a Meta-Font – galleys and initial proofs of two fonts (Box 1, Folder 17 (DT16))
    - Chapter 16: Lessons Learned from METAFONT – galleys (Box 1, Folder 18 (DT17))
    - Chapter 17: AMS Euler – A New Typeface for Mathematics – galleys, proofs of illustrations, and first proof of the typeface sample (Box 1, Folder 19 (DT18))
    - Chapter 18: Typesetting Concrete Mathematics – galley proof (Box 1, Folder 20 (DT19))
    - Chapter 19: A Course on METAFONT Programming – galleys and first proofs of illustrations (Box 1, Folder 21 (DT20))
    - Chapter 20: A Punk Meta-Font – galleys (Box 1, Folder 22 (DT21))
    - Chapter 21: Fonts for Digital Halftones – galleys and some test pages supplied by the printer (Box 1, Folder 23 (DT22))
    - Chapter 22: Digital Halftones by Dot Diffusion – galleys (Box 1, Folder 24 (DT23))
    - Chapter 23: A Note on Digitized Angles – galleys (Box 1, Folder 25 (DT24))
    - Chapter 24: TEXDR.AFT – Knuth's trial proof dated 14 June 1998 (Box 1, Folder 26 (DT25))
    - Chapter 25: TEX.ONE – Knuth's trial proof dated 14 June 1998 (Box 1, Folder 27 (DT26))
    - Chapter 26: TeX Incunabula – galleys (Box 1, Folder 28 (DT27))
    - Chapter 27: Icons for TeX and METAFONT – galleys (Box 1, Folder 29 (DT28))
    - Chapter 28: Computers and Typesetting – galleys and draft of new material (Box 1, Folder 30 (DT29))
    - Chapter 29: The New Versions of TeX and METAFONT – galleys (Box 1, Folder 31 (DT30))
    - Chapter 30: The Future of TeX and METAFONT – galleys (Box 1, Folder 32 (DT31))
    - Chapter 31: Questions and Answers, I – galleys (Box 1, Folder 33 (DT32))
    - Chapter 32: Questions and Answers, II – galleys (Box 1, Folder 34 (DT33))
    - Chapter 33: Questions and Answers, III – galleys (Box 1, Folder 35 (DT34))
    - Working copy of the entire book: pp. vii-65 (Box 1, Folder 36 (DT35))
    - Working copy of the entire book: pp. 67-155 (Box 1, Folder 37 (DT35))
    - Working copy of the entire book: pp. 157-223 (Box 1, Folder 38 (DT35))
    - Working copy of the entire book: pp. 225-313 (Box 1, Folder 39 (DT35))
    - Working copy of the entire book: pp. 315-414 (Box 1, Folder 40 (DT35))
    - Working copy of the entire book: pp. 415-545 (Box 1, Folder 41 (DT35))
    - Working copy of the entire book: pp. 547-end (Box 1, Folder 42 (DT35))
  - Analysis of Algorithms
    - Correspondence, 1997-2000 (Box 1, Folder 43 (AA1))
    - Preface (Box 1, Folder 44 (AA2))
    - Chapter 1: Mathematical Analysis of Algorithms – copy of original article, galleys, copy of a bibliographic item (Box 1, Folder 45 (AA3))
    - Chapter 2: The Dangers of Computer Science Theory – copy of original article, galleys (Box 1, Folder 46 (AA4))
    - Chapter 3: The Analysis of Algorithms - copy of original article, galleys (Box 1, Folder 47 (AA5))
    - Chapter 4: Big Omicron and Big Omega and Big Theta - copy of original article, galleys (Box 1, Folder 48 (AA6))
    - Chapter 5: Optimal Measurement Points for Program Frequency Counts - copy of original article, galleys (Box 1, Folder 49 (AA7))
    - Chapter 6: Estimating the Efficiency of Backtrack Programs – copy of letter to I. J. Good, 1975, copy of original article, galleys, proofs of new illustrations (Box 1, Folder 50 (AA8))
    - Chapter 7: Ordered Hash Tables – notes, copy of original article, galleys (Box 1, Folder 51 (AA9))
    - Chapter 8: Activity in an Interleaved Memory – copy of original article, galleys (Box 1, Folder 52 (AA10))
    - Chapter 9: An Analysis of Alpha-Beta Pruning – copy of relevant correspondence, copy of original article, galleys, first proofs of illustrations, draft of addendum (Box 1, Folder 53 (AA11))
    - Chapter 10: Notes on Generalized Dedekind Sums – notes, copy of original article, galleys (Box 1, Folder 54 (AA12))
    - Chapter 11: The Distribution of Continued Fraction Approximations – copy of original article, galleys (Box 1, Folder 55 (AA13))
    - Chapter 12: Evaluation of Porter's Constant – copy of original article, correspondence from John Wrench, galleys, draft of addendum (Box 1, Folder 56 (AA14))
    - Chapter 13: The Subtractive Algorithm for Greatest Common Divisors – copy of correspondence with co-author A. C. Yao, galleys, draft of addendum (Box 1, Folder 57 (AA15))
    - Chapter 14: Length of Strings for a Merge sort – copy of original article, galleys, draft of addendum (Box 1, Folder 58 (AA16))
    - Chapter 15: The Average Height of Planted Plane Trees – corrections, copy of original article, galleys, proofs of illustrations (Box 1, Folder 59 (AA17))
    - Chapter 16: The Toilet Paper Problem – copy of original article and one of its sequels, galleys, proofs of illustrations (Box 1, Folder 60 (AA18))
    - Chapter 17: An Analysis of Optimum Caching – letter from H. S. Wilf, copy of original and related articles, galleys (Box 1, Folder 61 (AA19))
    - Chapter 18: A Trivial Algorithm Whose Analysis Isn't – copies of related correspondence, copy of original article, galleys (Box 1, Folder 62 (AA20))
    - Chapter 19: Deletions That Preserve Randomness – copy of original article, galleys, references used in preparing addendum (Box 1, Folder 63 (AA21))
    - Chapter 20: Analysis of a Simple Factorization Algorithm – notes, copy of original article, galleys (Box 1, Folder 64 (AA22))
    - Chapter 21: The Expected Linearity of a Simple Equivalence Algorithm – notes, copy of original article, galleys, draft of addendum (Box 1, Folder 65 (AA23))
    - Chapter 22: Textbook Examples of Recursion – copies of related correspondence 1990-96, galleys, correspondence 2000 regarding error and its correction (Box 1, Folder 66 (AA24))
    - Chapter 23: An Exact Analysis of Stable Allocation – correspondence re the bibliography, galleys (Box 1, Folder 67 (AA25))
    - Chapter 24: Stable Husbands – galleys (Box 1, Folder 68 (AA26))
    - Chapter 25: Shellsort With Three Increments – copy of original article, galleys (Box 1, Folder 69 (AA27))
    - Chapter 26: The Average Time for Carry Propagation – copy of original article, galleys (Box 1, Folder 70 (AA28))
    - Chapter 27: Linear Probing and Graphs – related correspondence, copy of original article, galleys (Box 1, Folder 71 (AA29))
    - Chapter 28: A Terminological Proposal – copy of original article, galleys (Box 1, Folder 72 (AA30))
    - Chapter 29: Postscript about NP-Hard Problems – copy of original article, galleys (Box 1, Folder 73 (AA31))
    - Chapter 30: An Experiment in Optimal Sorting – copy of original article, galleys (Box 1, Folder 74 (AA32))
    - Chapter 31: Duality in Addition Chains – copy of original article, galleys (Box 1, Folder 75 (AA33))
    - Chapter 32: Complexity Results for Bandwidth Minimization – correspondence with co-author David Johnson, copy of original article, galleys, citations used in preparing the addendum (Box 1, Folder 76 (AA34))
    - Chapter 33: The Problem of Compatible Representatives – copy of original article, galleys (Box 1, Folder 77 (AA35))
    - Chapter 34: The Complexity of Nonuniform Random Number Generation – copy of original article, galleys, proofs of illustrations (Box 1, Folder 78 (AA36))
    - Working copy of the entire book: pp. vii-75 (Box 2, Folder 1 (AA37))
    - Working copy of the entire book: pp. 77-148 (Box 2, Folder 2 (AA37))
    - Working copy of the entire book: pp. 149-256 (Box 2, Folder 3 (AA37))
    - Working copy of the entire book: pp. 257-390 (Box 2, Folder 4 (AA37))
    - Working copy of the entire book: pp. 391-492 (Box 2, Folder 5 (AA37))
    - Working copy of the entire book: pp. 493-end (Box 2, Folder 6 (AA37))
  - MMIXware
    - MMIX in 1991 and 1992 – first and second draft of the program, presentation letter to John Hennessy, and his comments (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - MMIX-PIPE, 17 January 1999 – earliest printed draft with handwritten corrections (Box 3, Folder 2)